hello everybody and welcome to our for
大家好，欢迎来到我们第四期的
GMOD LUA tutorial series now in this
GMOD LUA教程，这一期
video again we're not gonna be going too
我们同样不会涉及到太多
much into scripting and I do apologize
直接编写代码的工作，再次
for guys who want to really get into the
对那些想要直接上手搞一些
more advanced stuff but I just need to
很高端的东西的观众说声抱歉，因为我需要
make sure that people who are new
确保那些编程新手
understand the these fundamental things
理解一些至关重要的基础内容
so in this video I'm gonna explain some
这一期视频里，我将讲解一些
things about data types now we're in in
关于数据类型的知识，在此前的
my lua tutorial series if you've ever
LUA教程系列里，如果你看过的话
watched it we went over some data types
我们曾经过了一遍基础的数据类型
and some of those were pools numbers
其中有bool型,数字型
strings you know there was a few data
字符型，还有诸如
types like their tables now in Garry's
table(表)这样的类型，在Garry's Mod里
Mod we're gonna be using more of these
我们将会使用更多的类型
and some of these will include player
其中就包括Player(玩家)数据类型
data types entity data types let's go
entity(实体)数据类型，还有
over some more metadata or metatables
更多像metadata或者metatable这样的类型
as well that's just a few there will be
这只是其中一小部分
a lot more um so what I'm gonna do here
还有更多的类型，所以
is I'm gonna go ahead and bring up the
我将要做的就是打开
wiki for Garry's Mod now on the wiki if
Garry's Mod的wiki。现在看,wiki上
you go to classes here you can see all
你可以展开左侧的类型(classes)栏目，你就可以看到
of the different basically data types or
所有基础的数据类型，亦或是
classes that we're gonna be working with
高级的"类"，这些就是我们将要用到的
and you can see player is one of them
你可以看到Player类就是其中之一
now I don't expect you to be using all
我并没有指望你用上所有
of these but fundamental ones like
这些类型，而是要了解一些基础的类型
player and entities are ones that we're
像是玩家(Player)或者实体(Entities)类，这些是我们
gonna be using so when when I'm storing
经常用到的。当我把一些东西
something in a variable like if I did
储存到一个变量里的时候，例如我
something like test is equal to localplayer()
让一个名为test的变量等于一个localplayer()
which again doesn't make sense to
可能现在对你来说这句话还没有什么清晰的意义
you now but well soon you may be
但很快你一定会开始想
wondering well what this test hold does
这个test变量究竟存了些什么
it hold the number does it hold the
存的是数字，还是
string does it hold the pool well no it
字符串，还是bool值，实际上它存的是
holds the metadata for the player now as
玩家的metadata，正如我说的
I said there is a few of these we will
这些数据类型都是我们将要用到的，我们将会
be going over them and yeah so I just
在之后的视频区了解，所以现在我只是
wanted to make sure that you understand
想让你理解
that when I refer to playa de Ayer or
当我提到playerdata或者
NPC Day or anything like that that's
npcdata的时候，或者类似的东西的时候
what we're gonna be referring to again I
我们是指代一种数据类型
apologize a short video but in the next
很抱歉这几期比较短没有什么干货，但在下一期视频里
one we should actually be getting
我们就要做一些
started on some code in and running some
实际能在游戏里运行的脚本了
functions so I hope you enjoyed the
希望你看的愉快
video I hope you learned something and
也学到了一些东西
I'll see you in the next video thanks
我们下期视频再见
for watching
感谢收看
字幕翻译By:Rainsfield.SK